aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Born! Brave High School Students
탄생! 용자 고교생
Space Dust Sandol Seijin
Appears
우주 모래먼지 샌들 성인 등장
It disappeared!
사라졌잖아?!
You're 10 years too early invade, you alien punks!
침략 따윈 10년은 빠르다구, 우주인 놈들아!
You must be En Daidouji, a freshman of Sankai High School.
산카이 고등학교 1학년 다이도우지 엔이지?
You should be grounded in your home, for your troubles with a student from another school.
너는 타 학교 학생과의 문제로 일주일간 자택 근신일 터다
Who the heck are you? Are you a friend of that guy?
누구냐, 넌?
그 녀석이랑 한패냐?
Stand up.
일어나라
If you're gonna fight, then wait outside. I'm busy fighting against aliens.
한판 뜨고 싶으면 밖에서 기다리라구
지금 우주인이랑 교전중이라서 말이야
Why you-!
이자식!
Stand up. I'll take you home.
일어나라, 집까지 바래다주마
Don't make me laugh! Do you think I'm a child?
농담하지 말라구!
내가 꼬맹이로 보이냐?
(Don't say! 4 or 5: 1-to-1 conversion from 四の五の言うな. Do not grumble!)
(Don't say! 4 or 5: 四の五の言うな의 영어 직역. 투덜대지 말 것.)
-Don't say 4 or 5.
-Wh- what?
-Don't say! 4 or 5
-뭐, 뭐야?
I am the chief of disciplines, Kai Hirose, a junior of Sankai High School.
산카이 고등학교 2학년, 풍기 위원장 히로세 카이
You were unlucky.
운 나쁜 녀석이군
Thank you very much.
감사합니다
I don't know what to say!
뭐라 감사의 말씀을 드려야 할지…
-Miss, are you free today?
-Huh?
-아가씨, 오늘 한가해?
-네?
I am Shin Sawamura. Would you like to go to a karaoke with me?
난 사와무라 신 함께 노래방이라도 가지 않을래?
Uh, but...
아… 하지만…
Is it you again, you demonic chief?
또 너냐, 귀신 풍기위원장?
Don't disgrace our high school, Shin.
고등학교 이름에 먹칠하지 마라, 신
Your third-stage Judo is crying.
유도 3단이 운다
Don't say something so stupid! I am just trying to sing my sound youth!
말도 안되는 소리 마! 난 단지 건전한 청춘을 구가(謳歌)하려고 말이야
Who's that?
저녀석은?
Here it is!
아, 있다!
A bookworm! It's a rare one!
미즈야마토시미다! 이거 참 드문 일인걸
What's wrong, miss?
무슨 일이신가요, 아가씨?
If you're looking for something, I can help...
찾는게 있다면 내가 도와줄…
Please don't step on the precious evidence!
귀중한 증거를 밟지 말아줘!
-You-!
-What is it, En? Weren't you supposed to be grounded in your home?
-너…?
-뭐야, 엔? 자택 근신 아니었어?
-Like you care.
-Do you know her?
-신경 꺼
-아는 사이냐?
Maria Tobe, from the same class.
같은 반의 토베 마리아야
What are you doing in such a place?
이런 곳에서 뭘 하고 있는 거지?
Dowsing, or in other words, I'm investigating spiritual phenomenons.
영사(靈査), 다시말해 심령현상 조사야
Is your classmate alright?
제정신이냐, 니네 반 친구?
Did you know that there was a fire around here last night?
어젯밤 이 근처에서 화재가 났던거 알아?
Firetrucks and ambulances were dispatched, but here, two of them were...
소방차랑 구급자가 출동했는데 그중 2대가 여기서…
Did you see a ghost or something?
유령이라도 목격했다는 거야?
Look at this skid marks.
이 타이어 자국을 봐
There were many eyewitnesses who saw two vehicles suddenly disappearing.
여러명의 목격자가 지켜보는 가운데 2대의 자동차가 돌연 소멸해 버린거야
Disappear? That's impossible.
소멸? 그런 말도 안되는…
Don't you watch the news?
뉴스도 안보니?
A jumbo jet, Shinkansen, and a fighter jet!
점보 제트기, 신간선, 전투기
There were five occurrences of this yesterday.
어제만 해도 5건의 사건이 일어났어
Do you think a ghost did that?
너는 그게 유령의 짓이라고 생각해?
Gaku?
가쿠?
What's wrong?
무슨 일이지?
My brother isn't here. He was with me moments ago...
동생이 안보여
좀전까지 같이 있었는데…
-I understand why he doesn't want to be with her.
-That's obvious.
-함께 있고 싶지 않은 마음, 알 것 같다
-동감이야
Kai! Shin!
카이! 신!
Yoku?
요쿠잖아?
-Run away!
-What?
-도망치세요!
-뭐?
Here.
자, 여기…
Thank you!
고마워요
We have breaking news.
뉴스를 전해드리겠습니다
Yesterday, a jumbo jet that mysteriously disappeared has suddenly reappeared in the place it disappeared.
어제 수수께끼의 소멸사건에 휘말린 점보 제트기가 소멸지와 같은 곳에서 돌연 모습을 나타내었고
Also, not only the Hokkaido, Jouetsu, Yamagata Shinkansens,
이어서 동해도, 죠우에츠, 산악형의 각 신간선 뿐만 아니라
but also a jet fighter are told to have appeared at their respective places.
제트 전투기도 소멸지점에서 속속 출연했다고 합니다
It's sand! It's raining sand!
모래잖아! 모래가 내리기 시작했어!
Could it be a spiritual phenomenon?!
설마, 심령현상?!잡아라!
This place is getting dangerous. Let's move.
여기도 위험해, 피하자
Stand back! Move away!
물러서세요! 더 물러서세요!
-Help me! Help me, Maria!
-Gaku, where are you?
-살려줘~ 살려줘, 누나~
-가쿠? 어디 있니?!
Look!
저기 봐!
Maria! Maria!
누나! 누나!
Gaku!
가쿠!
It's too dangerous! Stay back!
위험해, 물러서라!
Cover your head!
머리 숙여!
That's an eleventh grade student from our school!
저건 분명 우리 학교 1학년생입니다
It's Ryu!
류다!
Take my hand.
손 잡아.
Run!
뛰어!
Gaku!
가쿠!
What are you doing?!
어쩔 셈이냐?!
Isn't it obvious? I'm going to rescue them!
당연하잖아!
둘을 구하러 간다!
I will not forgive driving without a license!
무면허 운전은 용납 못한다!
This is youth!
이런게 바로 청춘이라구!
How often do you drive?
운전 경험은?
12~3 times! On a game, that is.
12~3번! 게임으로 말야
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
-Get in!
-En?
-타라!
-엔?
En!
엔!
-It's no good!
-We'll have to abandon the car.
-틀렸어!
-할 수 없다, 차를 버리자
-The door isn't opening!
-Same here!
-문이 안 열려!
-이쪽도 틀렸어!
-Alright, I'm going to save them!
-Wait, look at that!
-좋아, 구하러 가자!
-기다려 보세요, 저기!
What's this sound?
무슨 소리지?
Now!
지금이야!
If you don't hurry, the meteor will fall!
서두르지 않으면 운석이 떨어져요!
I'm opening the window!
창문을 열게
-Crawl out the window!
-Right!
-저기로 기어나가라!
-응!
-Gaku!
-Maria!
-가쿠
-누나!
Gaku!
가쿠!
-You two should go to somewhere safe first!
-Got it.
-둘은 먼저 피난해
-알았어
En?
엔?!
Those are the disappeared vehicles.
저건, 소멸 사건의 탈것이야
But they look a little different.
하지만 조금 모양이 다른 것 같아요
Where are we?
여기는 대체 어디지?
Dear earthlings.
지구인이여
Who are you?!
누구냐?!
(Seijin: 星人. literally star/planet person; alien)
Brave Seijin.
브레이브 성인(星人)
Brave Seijin?
브레이브… 성인?
I am a detective of the Space Police Organization.
우주 경찰 기구의 형사다
What are you going to do with us?!
우리들을 어쩔 셈이냐?!
Were you behind the sequence of disappearances?
일련의 소멸 사건은 너의 짓인가?
The Earth is being targeted.
지구는 지금 노려지고 있다
Prisoners from the Space Prison Sargasso have begun their planetary galley.
우주감옥 사르갓소의 죄수들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
Planetary galley?
혹성 사냥?
Sargasso is a prison camp of villainous aliens who dare to threaten the peace of the Space.
사르갓소는 우주의 평화를 위협하는 온갖 흉악한 우주인의 수용소다
But the prisoners broke out in revolt and took over Sargasso.
하지만 죄수들은 반란을 일으키고 사르갓소를 점거했다
And those bloodthirsty space criminals have chosen the Earth as their target.
그리고 피에 굶주린 우주 범죄자들은 지구를 목표로 선택한 거다
I made eight protection machines modeled from the vehicles of the Earth.
나는 지구의 탈것을 모델로 8대의 방위머신을 완성했다
All that remains are the Dagwons who will fight together with these machines.
남은건 머신과 함께 싸울 다그온이 필요하다만…
What is Dagwon?
다그온이란 건 뭐냐?
It is a word meaning brave hero in our language.
우리들의 별에서 용자(勇者)를 의미하는 말이다
But there is no time to carefully choose the right people.
하지만 이미 그런 인물을 선택할 시간은 없다
I will give you five gentlemen the ability to fight against the criminals from Sargasso.
너희들 5명에게 사르갓소의 범죄자와 싸울 능력을 내려주마
That sounds cool!
왠지 멋진데!
Wait! If they escaped from your prison, then shouldn't you take care of them?
기다려! 너희들의 감옥에서 탈출한 녀석들이라면 스스로 처리해라!
That's right! We have nothing to do with it!
그래, 우리하곤 관계 없다구
That's too arbitrary!
너무 멋대로예요
We have no time for that.
우리들에겐 그럴 여유가 없다
Your bodyguard robots.
너희들의 호위(Body Guard) 로봇이다
Dagwon gentlemen, I will entrust the peace of Earth to you.
다그온 제군, 지구의 평화는 자네들에게 맡기겠다
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Fire En!
파이어 엔!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Armor Shin!
아머 신!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Wing Yoku!
윙 요쿠!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류!
En!
엔!
Maria!
누나!
That's some power! With this...
엄청난 힘이야! 이거라면…
Shadow Kunai!
섀도우 쿠나이!
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!
Blizzard Hurricane!
블리자드 허리케인!
Turbo Wheel Attack!
터보 휠 어택!
Fire Bird Attack!
파이어 버드 어택!
-En!
-Yo!
-엔!
-여어!
En!
엔!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!
En!
엔!
Now it's a robot?!
이번엔 로봇이야!
This is awesome!
이, 이거 대단하구만!
Star Burn!
스타 번!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Shoot!
슛!
Cool!
멋지다~!
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
tomaru koto nai MELODY
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
tooku kirameita
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
The five of us have become Dagwon! Zargoss Seijin came to attack this time!
다그온이 되어버린 우리들 5명 이번엔 자고스 성인의 침략이다!
The city is rising and disks are flying!!
상승하는 도시, 덮쳐오는 거대한 원반!
It isn't working. Dag Fire isn't enough!
안돼! 다그 파이어로는 감당할 수 없어!
Right at that moment, Fire Jumbo appeared!
그 때 나타난 파이어 점보!
This body... Dag Fire is combining!
이 몸이… 다그 파이어가 합체한다!
What is this new power?
이 새로운 힘은 뭐냐?!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Midair City Maneuvers
다음회 용자지령 다그온
공중도시 작전
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!
Midair City Maneuvers
공중도시 작전